A Guide to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund records, Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, RG 6 FA1767
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Brothers Fund records, Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, RG 6
1957-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Brothers Fund
FA1767
33.42 Cubic Feet 41 containers, 38 scrapbooks
Biographical / Historical
Biography of President Ramon Magsaysay
Ramón del Fierro Magsaysay (b.August 31, 1907 – d.March 17, 1957) served as president of the Republic of the Philippines from December 30, 1953 until his death in a plane crash in 1957. President Magsaysay was best known for successfully defeating the communist-led Hukbalahap (Huk) movement, and for introducing reform to various aspects of Filipino life.(1) He was extremely popular with the Filipino people and was universally respected for his integrity and his dedication to the betterment of all humankind.
Magsaysay Credo
I believe that government starts at the bottom and moves upward, for government exists for the welfare of the masses of the nation. I believe that he who has less in life should have more in law. I believe that the little man is fundamentally entitled to a little bit more food in his stomach, a little more cloth in his back and a little more roof over his head. I believe that this nation is endowed with a vibrant and stout heart, and possesses untapped capabilities and incredible resiliency. I believe that a high and unwavering sense of morality should pervade all spheres of governmental activity. I believe that the pulse of government should be strong and steady, and the men at the helm imbued with missionary zeal. I believe in the majesty of constitutional and legal processes, in the inviolability of human rights. I believe that the free world is collectively strong, and that there is neither need or reason to compromise the dignity of man. I believe that communism is iniquity, as is the violence it does to the principles of Christianity. I believe that the President should set the example of a big heart, an honest mind, sound instincts, the virtue of healthy impatience and an abiding love for the common man.
Organizational History of the Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation
The Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation (RMAF) was established in 1957 in memory of the late President Magsaysay who died in a place crash that same year. President Magsaysay was well-known for his good nature and commitment to justice for all people. Consequently, his death devastated not just the people of the Philippines, but the global community which included the Rockefeller brothers. Just six weeks after learning of the death of Ramon Magsaysay, John D. Rockefeller 3rd wrote to President Carlos P. Garcia, who succeeded President Magsaysay, and proposed that an award be given in honor of President Magsaysay. He wrote:
"My brothers and I have followed closely President Magsaysay's life and work. We believe deeply in that for which he stood… The trustees of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund would consider it a privilege to have a part in establishing a living memorial to the late President. They have authorized me to suggest the creation of the Ramon Magsaysay Award to be given annually to one or more persons in Asia whose demonstrated leadership is motive by a concern for the welfare of people comparable to that which characterized the life of Ramon Magsaysay."(2)
President Garcia accepted the Rockefeller Brothers Fund's proposal. As described on the Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation's website, "[w]ith the concurrence of the Philippine government, the trustees of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF) established the Award to honor his memory and perpetuate his example of integrity in public service and pragmatic idealism within a democratic society".(3) The RBF supplied the initial endowment and the RMAF was formally organized in May 1957.
The RMAF is a non-profit corporation run by a seven person, all-Filipino, Board of Trustees. The RMAF is based in Manila, Philippines, and has operated out of the Ramon Magsaysay Center since 1968, when the building opened. Income earned from the Ramon Magsaysay Center has helps to support and sustain the RMAF.
The first awards were given in 1958. Since then, each year one award was given in each of the following five categories: Government Service (GS), Public Service (PS), Community Leadership (CL), Journalism and Literature (JL) and International Understanding (IU, later PIU). In 1964, the Journalism and Literature category was amended to include Creative Communication Arts (JLCCA). Then, in 2000, thanks to a grant from the Ford Foundation, a sixth category for Emergent Leadership (EL) was added. After 2008, the awards were no longer given according to category, except for Emergent Leadership. As described on the RMAF website, "[t]he Ramon Magsaysay Award is given to persons – regardless of race, nationality, creed or gender – who address issues of human development in Asia with courage and creativity, and in doing so have made contributions which have transformed their societies".(4) Since, 1958, the award has been given to a diverse group of individuals and organizations. The award ceremonies are held every year on August 31st, the anniversary of the birth of President Magsaysay. During the days surrounding the award ceremony, awardees and guests attend a series of events given in their honor. These events include the laying of wreaths at the Rizal Monument and in front of Ramon Magsaysay's tomb, luncheons for the awardees, and calls on the current President of the Philippines and on Mrs. Luz Magsaysay, the wife of President Magsaysay. Additionally, the awardees are asked to lead a discussion or give a presentation on a subject related to the work for which they were acknowledged.
Conditions Governing Access
All archival material 10 years old or older is open for research.
Scope and Contents
Contains a scrapbook for each year that the Ramon Magsaysay Award was given from 1958-1998, with the exception of 1996 and 1997. In each given year, a scrapbook was completed shortly after the award ceremonies had ended. The scrapbooks were then sent to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF).
The material within each scrapbook includes media coverage leading up to the award ceremony, documentation of the ceremony itself, and the post-event departures of the awardees. Most scrapbooks feature newspaper clippings, responses given by the awardees at the ceremonies, photographs of the various events related to the awards, and copies of materials handed out during informal group discussions given by the awardees.
There were no awards given in 1970 because the government of the Philippines asked that institutions conserve all foreign currency. No awards given in 1990 out of respect for the people of the Philippines who had just experienced a terrible earthquake on July 16th, 1990.
In this series, categories of awards will be abreviated in the following fashion:
Award Category Abbreviations are as follows: Government Service (GS) Public Service (PS) Community Leadership (CL) Journalism and Literature (JL) International Understanding (IU) Peace and International Understanding (PIU) Journalism, Literature and Creative Communication Arts (JLCCA) Emergent Leadership (EL)
Arrangement
This material is comprised of two series: Series 1: Scraphooks Series 2: Audiovisual materials
- Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, 1957-1998; 6; 33.42 Cubic Feet 41 containers, 38 scrapbooks
  - Scrapbooks, 1957-1998; 1; 30.11 Cubic Feet 36 phono record boxes; 38 scrapbooks
    Scope and Contents
    Contains a scrapbook for each year that the Ramon Magsaysay Award was given from 1958-1998, with the exception of 1996 and 1997. In each given year, a scrapbook was completed shortly after the award ceremonies had ended. The scrapbooks were then sent to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF).
    The material within each scrapbook includes media coverage leading up to the award ceremony, documentation of the ceremony itself, and the post-event departures of the awardees. Most scrapbooks feature newspaper clippings, responses given by the awardees at the ceremonies, photographs of the various events related to the awards, and copies of materials handed out during informal group discussions given by the awardees.
    There were no awards given in 1970 because the government of the Philippines asked that institutions conserve all foreign currency. No awards given in 1990 out of respect for the people of the Philippines who had just experienced a terrible earthquake on July 16th, 1990.
    In this series, categories of awards will be abreviated in the following fashion:
    Award Category Abbreviations are as follows: Government Service (GS) Public Service (PS) Community Leadership (CL) Journalism and Literature (JL) International Understanding (IU) Peace & International Understanding (PIU) Journalism, Literature and Creative Communication Arts (JLCCA) Emergent Leadership (EL)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Rockefeller Brothers Fund has donated this collection to the Rockefeller Archive Center. The Archive Center received the scrapbooks in multiple accessions beginning in 1979 and continuing periodically through 2006.
    Arrangement
    Arranged chronological by the year the award was given. Original order was maintained within each scrapbook, and pages numbers were assigned, found in the upper right-hand corner of each sleeve.
    Conditions Governing Access
    All archival material 10 years old or older is open for research.
    - 1958 (Box 1)
      Award Winners: Vinoba Bhave (CL); Chian Mon Lin (GS); Robert Dick and Mochtar Lubis (JLCCA); Operation Brotherhood (PIU); Mary Rutnam (PS)
    - 1959 (Box 2, Box 1)
      Award Winners: Jose Aguilar (GS); Dalai Lama (CL); Chintaman Deshmukh (GS); Edward Law Yone (JLCCA); Tee Tee Luce and Joaquin Vilallonga (PS); Tarzie Vittachi (JLCCA)
    - 1960 (Box 2, Box 3)
      Award Winners: Rahman Abdul (CL); Henry Holland and Ronald Holland (PS); Y.C. James Yen (PIU)
    - 1961 (Box 4, Box 3)
      Award Winners: Gus Borgeest (CL); Genevieve Caulfield (PIU); Amitabha Chowdhury (JLCCA); Raden Kodijat (GS); Nilawan Pintong (PS)
    - 1962 (Box 4, Box 5)
      Award Winners: Francisca Aquinto (GS); Chang Chun-ha (JLCCA); Horace Kadoorie and Lawrence Kadoorie (PS); Mother Teresa (PIU); Palayil Narayanan and Koesna Poeradiredja (CL)
    - 1963 (Box 6, Box 5)
      Award Winners: Akhter Khan (GS); Dara Khurody, Verghese Kurien and Tribhuvandas Patel (CL); Helen Kim (PS); US Peace Corps in Asia (PIU)
    - 1964 (Box 6, Box 7)
      Award Winners: Welthy Fisher (PIU); Augustine Hoa (PS); Yukiharu Miki (GS); Kayser Sung and Richard Wilson (JLCCA); Pablo Tapia (CL)
    - 1965 (Box 9, Box 8, Box 7)
      Award Winners: Bayanihan Folk Arts Center (PIU); Akira Kurosawa (JLCCA); Lim Kim San (CL); Jayaprakash Narayan (PS); Puey Ungphakorn (GS)
    - 1966 (Box 9)
      Award Winners: Kamaladevi Chattopadhyay (CL); Committee for Coordination of Investigations of the Lower Mekong Basin and Cooperating Entities (PIU); Kim Yong-ki (PS); Phon Sangsingkeo (GS)
    - 1967 (Box 10)
      Award Winners: Abdul Razak (CL); Sithiporn Kridakara (PS); Shiroshi Nasu (PIU); Satyajit Ray (JLCCA); Keo Viphakone (GS)
    - 1968 (Box 11)
      Award Winners: Cooperative for American Relief Everywhere (PIU); Rosario Encarnation and Silvino Encarnation (CL); Li Kwoh-ting (GS); Ton That Thien (JLCCA); Seiichi Tobata (PS)
    - 1969 (Box 12)
      Award Winners: Ahangamage Ariyaratne (CL); Hsu Shih-Chu (GS); International Rice Research Institute (PIU); Kim Hyung-Seo (PS); Mitoji Nishimoto (JLCCA)
    - 1971 (Box 13)
      Award Winners: Prayoon Chanyavongs (JLCCA); Saburo Okita (PIU); Pedro Orata (PS); Ali Sadikin (GS); Moncompu Sambasivan Swaminathan (CL)
    - 1972 (Box 13, Box 14)
      Award Winners: Goh Keng-Swee (GS); Cecile Guidote and Gilopez Kabayao (PS); Yasuji Hanamori (JLCCA); Hans Westernberg (CL)
    - 1973 (Box 14, Box 15)
      Award Winners: Krasae Chanawongse (CL); Antonio Fortich and Benjamin Gaston (PS); Michiko Ishimure (JLCCA); Balachandra Sekhar (GS); Summer Institute of Linguistics (PIU)
    - 1974 (Box 15, Box 16)
      Award Winners: Fusaye Ichikawa (CL); Hiroshi Kuroki (GS); William Materson (PIU); Zacarias Sarian (JLCCA); M.S. Subbulakshmi (PS)
    - 1975 (Box 16, Box 17)
      Award Winners: Lee Tai-Young (CL); Patrick James McGlinchey (PIU); Phra Parnchand (PS); Mohammed Suffian (GS); Boobli George Verghese (JLCCA)
    - 1976 (Box 17, Box 18)
      Award Winners: Hermenegild Fernandez (PS); Henning Holck-Larson (PIU); Sombhu Mitra (JLCCA); Elsie Tu (GS); Toshikazu Wakatsuki (CL)
    - 1977 (Box 18, Box 19)
      Award Winners: Ela Ramesh Bhatt (CL); College of Agriculture at the University of the Philippines at Los Banos (PIU); Fe Del Mundo (PS); Benjamin Galstaun (GS); Mahesh Regmi (JLCCA)
    - 1978 (Box 19, Box 20)
      Award Winners: Tahrunnesa Abdullah (CL); Shahrum bin Yub (GS); Soedjatmoko (PIU); Prateep Ungsongtham-Hata (PS); Yoon Suk-joong (JLCCA)
    - 1979 (Box 21, Box 20)
      Award Winners: Mabelle Arole and Rajanikant Arole (CL); Association of Southeast Asian Nations (PIU); Chang Kee-ryo (PS); Lokukamkanamge Manjusri (JLCCA); Raden Wasito (GS)
    - 1980 (Box 21, Box 22)
      Award Winners: Fazle Hazan Abed (CL); Muhammed Alias (GS); Francisco Sionil Jose (JLCCA); Shigeharu Matsumoto (PIU); Ohm Dae-sup (PS)
    - 1981 (Box 22, Box 23)
      Award Winners: Gour Kishore Ghosh (JLCCA); Augustine Joung Kang (PIU); Johanna Nasution (PS); Pramod Karan Sethi (CL); Prawase Wasi (GS)
    - 1982 (Box 23, Box 24)
      Award Winners: Arturo Alcaraz (GS); Chandi Prasad Bhatt (CL); Manibhai Desai (PS); Arun Shourie (JLCCA)
    - 1983 (Box 25, Box 24)
      Award Winners: Fua Hariphitak (PS); Marcelline Jayakody (JLCCA); Aloysius Schwartz (PIU); ANton Soedjarwo (CL); SU Nan-cheng (GS)
    - 1984 (Box 25, Box 26)
      Award Winners: Jiro Kawakita (PIU); Rasipuram Laxman (JLCCA); Thongbai Thongpao (PS); Wu Ta-you (GS); Muhammad Yunus (CL)
    - 1985 (Box 26, Box 27)
      Award Winners: Murlidhar Amte (PS); Lino Brocka (JLCCA); Zafrullah Chowdhury (CL); Tan Sri Noordin (GS); Harold Ray Watson (PIU)
    - 1986 (Box 27, Box 28)
      Award Winners: John Vincent Daly and Paul Jei (CL); Abdul Sattar Edhi and Bilqis Edhi (PS); International Institute of Rural Reconstruction (PIU); Aloysius Mboi and Nafsiah Mboi (GS); Radio Veritas (JLCCA)
    - 1987 (Box 28)
      Award Winners: Haji Hanafiah (GS); Hans Bague Jassin (PS); RIchard William Timm (PIU); Aree Valyasevi (CL); Diane (Yun-Peng) Ying (JLCCA)
    - 1988 (Box 29)
      Award Winners: Masanobu Fukuoka (PS); Miriam Santiago (GS); Veditantirige Sarachchandra (JLCCA); The Royal Project (PIU); Mohammad Yeasin (CL)
    - 1989 (Box 30)
      Asian Institute of Technology (PIU); Zakiah Hanum (GS); Lakshimi Chand Jain (PS); Kim Im-Soon (CL); James Reuter (JLCCA)
    - 1991 (Box 32, Box 31, Box 30)
      Award Winners: Alfredo Bengzon (GS); Shih Cheng-Yen (CL); Press Foundation of Asia (PIU); Princess Maha Sirindhorn (PS); K.V. Subbanna (JLCCA)
    - 1992 (Box 32)
      Award Winners: Angel Alcala (PS); Shoaib Khan (CL); Ravi Shankar (JLCCA); Chamlong Srimuang (GS); Washington Sycip (PIU)
    - 1993 (Box 33, Box 32)
      Award Winners: Banoo Jehangir Coyaji (PS); Noboru Iwamura (PIU); Bienvenido Lumbera (JLCCA); Abdurrahman Wahid (CL); Vo-Tong Xuan (GS)
    - 1994 (Box 33, Box 34)
      Award Winners: Eduardo Jorge Anzorena (PIU); Kiran Bedi (GS); Fei Xiaotong and Sima Samar (CL); Abdul Samad Ismail (JLCCA); Mechai Viravaidya (PS)
    - 1995 (Box 35, Box 34)
      Award Winners: Asian Institute of Management (PIU); Morihiko Hiramatsu (GS); Teh Ho Ming (CL); Asma Jahangir (PS); Pramoedya Ananta Toer (JLCCA)
    - 1998 (Box 36)
      Corazon Aquino (IU); Nuon Phaly (CL); Syed Adibul Rizvi (GS); Sophon Suphapong (PS); Ying Ruocheng (JLCCA)
  - Audiovisual recordings, 1958-1995; 2; 3.31 Cubic Feet 17 audio reels, 24 moving images, 5 containers
    - The 1958 Magsaysay Awards Ceremony - Tape 1, 1958 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15841)
      Access copy available.
    - The 1958 Magsaysay Awards Ceremony - Tape 2, 1958 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15842)
    - The 1958 Magsaysay Awards Ceremony - Tape 3, 1958 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15843)
      Comments by Awardees: 1. Dr. Mary Rutnam; 2. Mr. Oscar Arellano; 3. Mr. R. McCulloch Dick; 4. Mr. Carlos Nievera for MochtarLubis; 5. Dr. Chiang Mon-Lin
    - The 1961 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 1, 1961 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15844)
      Ramon Magsaysay Awards Foundation Presentation Ceremonies. 4:00 P.M. Philamlife Auditorium, Manila, Philippines. From remarks by Hon. Rocardo Paras to Reading of the Citations (Mr. F. San Juan).
    - The 1961 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 2, 1961 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15845)
      From Reading of Citations to Response by Awardees (Gus Borgeest)
    - The 1961 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 3, 1961 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15846)
      From Response by Awardees (Genevieve Caulfield to Amitabha Chowdhury)
    - The 1962 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 1, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15847)
      Magsaysay Ceremonies: 1. Remarks by Juge G. Santos. 2. Reading of Citations: A.) Chang Chung-Ha by Baldomero Olivetia. B.) Mother Teresa by F. Sah Juan
    - The 1962 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 2, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15848)
      Magsaysay Awards: 1. Reading of Citation for Kadoorie Brothers (Horace Kadoorie and Lawrence Kadoorie) by D. Umali. 2. Reading of Citation for Harley Koesna Poeradiredja and Palayil Namayanan by G. Santos.
    - The 1962 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 3, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15849)
      Magsaysay Ceremonies: 1. Citation Reading for Francisca Reyes Aquino by J. Vargas. 2. Responses by Chang Chun-Ha and Lawrence Kadoorie
    - The 1962 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 4, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15850)
      Magsaysay Awards - Responses: 1. Horace Kadoorie 2. Palayil Narayanan 3. Francisca Reyes Aquino 4. Mother Teresa
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Audio begins at 3:45.
    - The 1963 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 2, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15851)
    - The 1963 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 3, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15852)
    - The 1964 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 1, 1964 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15853)
      Presentation Ceremonies
    - The 1964 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 2, 1964 August 31; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15854)
    - The 1964 Magsaysay Awards - Tape 3, 1964 August 31 (Box 5, Reel AV 15855)
      1/4 inch audio tape
    - Mr. R. Sargent Shriver's Speech and Open Forum Manila Overseas Press Club - Tape 1, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15856)
    - Mr. R. Sargent Shriver's Speech and Open Forum Manila Overseas Press Club - Tape 2, 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5, Reel AV 15857)
    - Bangkok - Henry Kissinger Interview, 1987; Umatic (Box 1, Tape AV 13034)
      Visnews
    - Bangkok - Following Opening, Final Press Conference, 1987 November 14; Umatic (Box 1, Tape AV 13035)
      Visnews: 1. Magsaysay ends. 2. Press Conference.
    - Bangkok - Gala Dinner, 1987 November 14; Umatic (Box 1, Tape AV 13036)
      Visnews: 1. Awardees dinner
    - Bangkok - Closing Session, 1987 November 14; Umatic (Box 1, Tape AV 13037)
      Visnews: Closing Session - Tape 1 of 2
    - Bangkok - Reception and Asian Dinner, David Rockefeller Interview, 1987 November 12-13; Umatic (Box 1, Tape AV 13038)
      Visnews: 1. Gala Dinner. 2. David Rockefeller Sr. Interview
    - Bangkok - VIP Arrivals at Gala Dinner, Dinner Speeches, 1987 November 14; Umatic (Box 1, Tape AV 13039)
      Visnews: 1. Magsaysay Awardees Dinner
    - VISNEWS: Edited Video News Release of the Magsaysay Awardees Assembly, 1987 November 12; Umatic (Box 1, Tape AV 13040)
      Distributed by VISNEWS with Asian regional/Eastern European satellite pick up.
    - Manila - Raw Footage for Video Release, 1987; Umatic (Box 2, Tape AV 13041)
      Ramon Magsaysay Awards
    - Manila - Raw Footage for Video Release, 1987; Umatic (Box 2, Tape AV 13042)
    - Manila - Raw Footage for Video Release, 1987; Umatic (Box 2, Tape AV 13043)
      General
      Umatic
    - Manila - Palace Visit, 1987 September 1; Umatic (Box 2, Tape AV 13044)
      Courtesy Call - Ramon Magsaysay Awardee
    - Manila - Palace Visit, 1987 September 1; Umatic (Box 2, Tape AV 13045)
    - Manila - Rizal Monument, Philamlife Auditorium, RM Photo, Manila View, 1987; Umatic (Box 2, Tape AV 13046)
      Tape 1: Rizal Monument at Rizal Park (various angles); 2. Philippine Flag at Luneta; 3. Rizal Monument (close-ups); 4. Philam Building; 5. RM Photo; 6. Manila at Top of Hilton
    - Manila - Wreath-laying by Awardees at Rizal Monument, 1987; Umatic (Box 2, Tape AV 13047)
      Tape 2: Wreath-laying of Ramon Magsaysay Awardees at Rizal Monument
    - Manila - Wreath-laying by Awardees at President Magsaysay's Tomb, 1987; Umatic (Box 3, Tape AV 13048)
      Tape 3: Wreath-laying of Ramon MagsaysayAwardees at President Magsaysay's Tomb in North Cemetary
    - Manila - Award Ceremony at The Philamlife Auditorium - Part 1, 1987; Umatic (Box 3, Tape AV 13049)
      Tape 4: Start of Ramon Magsaysay Awarding Ceremonies at the Philamlife Auditorium
    - Manila - Award Ceremony at The Philamlife Auditorium - Part 2, 1987; Umatic (Box 3, Tape AV 13050)
      Tape 5: Continuation of Reading of Citations of Ramon Magsaysay Awardees
    - Manila - Award Ceremony Responses - Part 1, 1987; Umatic (Box 3, Tape AV 13051)
      Tape 6: Responses of Awardees: Malaysian, Indonesian, Thai, Chinese
    - Manila - Award Ceremony Responses - Part 2 and Cocktail Reception, 1987; Umatic (Box 3, Tape AV 13052)
      Tape 7: Presponses End of Chinese Awardee response and American response
    - Interview with Diane Ying, 1987 September 18; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13053)
      1987 Awardee - Taiwan - CTS 1:30-1:38 P.M.
    - Magsaysay - Thai Television Channel 9, 1987 November 13-14; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13054)
    - Golden Earth (English), 1988; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13061)
      Produced by the Bayanihan Folk Arts Association
    - The A-Frame (English), 1988; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13062)
    - The Cordilleras, 1990; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13060)
    - The Sound of Tambours: An ASEAN Tapestry in Music and Dance, 1991; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13059)
      Produced by the Bayanihan Folk Arts Center
    - The 1994 Ramon Magsaysay Awards Presentation Ceremonies, 1994 August 31; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13055)
      Cultural Center of the Philippines, Manila
    - The 1994 Ramon Magsaysay Awards - Awardees Activities, 1994 August 30-31; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13056)
      Manila, Philippines
    - The 1994 Ramon Magsaysay Awards, 1994 August 30-31; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13057)
    - The 1995 Ramon Magsaysay Awards, 1995 August 30-31; VHS (Box 4, Tape AV 13058)